Guide to the Rachel Fuller Brown Notebooks 1920-1926
University of Chicago Library
Brown, Rachel Fuller. Notebooks
1920-1926
2.5 linear ft. (5 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Rachel Fuller Brown Notebooks collection consists chiefly of class and laboratory notes relating to chemistry courses taken during Brown's years at the University. Included also are notes and materials from a summer course taken at Harvard University. These materials have been arranged in three series: notes identified by the name of the instructor and the course number; notes identified only by course or subject; and miscellaneous notebooks.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Biographical Note
Rachel Fuller Brown (1898-1980) began graduate study in chemistry at the University in 1920 after graduating from Mount Holyoke College. She received her M.A. in Chemistry in 1921 and, in 1926, after completing her course work for a doctorate, went to work for the New York State Department of Health's Laboratories and Research Division. Brown spent the next forty-three years there working and researching in the area of antibiotics. In 1933 she received her Ph.D. in Chemistry from the University.
Scope Note
The Rachel Fuller Brown Notebooks collection consists chiefly of class and laboratory notes relating to chemistry courses taken during Brown's years at the University. Included also are notes and materials from a summer course taken at Harvard University. These materials have been arranged in three series: notes identified by the name of the instructor and the course number; notes identified only by course or subject; and miscellaneous notebooks.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Brown, Rachel Fuller, 1898-1980; University of Chicago. Department of Chemistry; Chemistry; Chemistry - Study and Teaching; Lecture Notes; Laboratory Not
INVENTORY
- Series I: Course Notes Identified by Instructor and Course Number
  - Branham, Sarah Elizabeth. Bact 2A. The Pathogenic Bacteria. Winter, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Falk, Isidore Sydney. Bact. General Bacteriology Autumn, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frederich, William John. Bact 12. Public Health Laboratory Methods. Spring, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harkins, William Draper. Chem 386. Radioactiview. Winter, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jordan, Edwin Oakes and Falk, Isidore Sydney. Bact 3. Public Hygiene. Autumn 1924. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nicolet, Ben H. Chem 35. Organic Preparations. Autumn 1920. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rising, Mary Meda. Chem 6. Qualitative Analysis. Spring, 1925., Rising, Chem. 7. Qualitative Analysis. Winter, 1925. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rising, Chem 334. Organic Nitrogen Derivatives. Winter, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rising, Chem 10. Advanced Qualitative Analysis. Spring, 1925. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Schlesinger, Hermann Irving. Chem 50. Inorganic Preparations. Winter, 1925. Rising, Chem 55A. Advanced Inorganic Chemistry. Autumn, 1924. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Senior, James Kuhn. Chem 41A. Stereochemistry. Spring, 1925. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stieglitz, Julius, Chem 31. Organic Chemistry. Winter, 1925. Chem 32. Organic Chemistry. Spring, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stieglitz, Julius, Chem 321. Organic Chemistry. Autumn, 1925. Chem 90. Research in Organic and Physico-Organic Chemistry. Autumn 1925. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Terry-McCoy, Ethel Mary. Introduction to Colloid Chemistry. Summer, 1925. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II: Course Notes by Course or Subject Only
  - Bact 410. Advanced Bacteriology, Parasitology, and Immunology. Summer/Autumn 1925. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chemistry of Foods. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Chemistry. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Quantitative Analysis. Harvard Summer School, 1924. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Organic Chemistry, Organic Chemistry 1. Organic Chemistry 2. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chem 39. Organic Ultimate Analysis. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Physical Chemistry., Physical Chemistry 1. Physical Chemistry 2. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series III: Miscellaneous Notebooks
  - Reading Notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Experiment Notebook (Box 5, Folder 3)